<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Negar Mokhberian | DataFirst</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/negar-mokhberian/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/negar-mokhberian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Negar Mokhberian</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Negar Mokhberian</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/negar-mokhberian/</link></image><item><title>Understanding the Relation Between Noise and Bias in Annotated Datasets</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2023-fall/821/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2023-fall/821/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When it comes to classification tasks, many previous work has tried to design larger and more complex neural networks. Recently, the line of data-centric AI has worked on shifting the focus to the quality of the train data. This shift arises from the recognition that the annotations associated with dataset instances can exhibit both noise, stemming from vague instructions or human errors, and bias, arising from differing perspectives among annotators in response to given prompts.
In this project, our objective is to bridge the gap between the two lines of research: one dedicated to identifying noisy instances and the other striving to account for the diverse perspectives of annotators. Specifically, we will delve into the domain of offensive text detection datasets, a highly subjective task. Our investigation will center on whether perspectivist classification models have effectively harnessed valuable information from instances flagged as noisy by noise-detection techniques.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/negar-mokhberian">Negar Mokhberian&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PyTorch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fine-tuning language models in Huggingface package&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Connections within Contemporary Feminism Movements</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-spring/305/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-spring/305/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This project will look at events data collected at several recent feminist social movements and understand their connection to each other. Specifically, it will explore individuals or organizations that played instrumental role in movement mobilization, relationship brokerage between movements, and building and sustaining activist communities. Previous research suggests that those distinctive movements are often not isolated incidents, but mobilized by a core group of “leaders” or similar ideas and frames. The goal is to understand how seemingly disconnected movements relate to one another help to reveal the lasting impact of mediated movements.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Interdisciplinary Data Science Team&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Keerti Bhogaraju&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ian Myoungsu Choi&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Negar Mokhberian&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Nazanin Alipourfard&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/aimei-yang">Aimei Yang&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Social Network Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Mining&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>