<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sowmiya Mathanagopalan | DataFirst</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/sowmiya-mathanagopalan/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/sowmiya-mathanagopalan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Sowmiya Mathanagopalan</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Sowmiya Mathanagopalan</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/sowmiya-mathanagopalan/</link></image><item><title>Human Bio-signals as a Function of Indoor Air Quality Control for Human Health in Buildings</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2023-spring/4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2023-spring/4/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the COVID, the remote work environment has become popular, and many commercial offices have tried to keep both the in-person work environment and the remote work environment while attempting to reduce the size of their workplaces. Even though hot desking systems are increasingly common and even starting to feel like a trend these days, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much data to show how such systems can support occupants&amp;rsquo; environmental comfort, work productivity, and psychological stability while they are at work. Therefore, this project focuses on investigating how much the occupants are satisfied with their new workplace platform and how much a hotdesking system affects their work productivity, environmental satisfaction, etc. The project&amp;rsquo;s findings will help design this new desking system in a way that will increase occupants&amp;rsquo; satisfaction with their surroundings and productivity at work without compromising their quality of life in the workplace.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Human Bio-signals as a Function of Indoor Air Quality Control for Human Health in Buildings</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2023-spring/807/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2023-spring/807/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After the COVID, the remote work environment has become popular, and many commercial offices have tried to keep both the in-person work environment and the remote work environment while attempting to reduce the size of their workplaces. Even though hot desking systems are increasingly common and even starting to feel like a trend these days, there isn't much data to show how such systems can support occupants' environmental comfort, work productivity, and psychological stability while they are at work. Therefore, this project focuses on investigating how much the occupants are satisfied with their new workplace platform and how much a hotdesking system affects their work productivity, environmental satisfaction, etc. The project's findings will help design this new desking system in a way that will increase occupants' satisfaction with their surroundings and productivity at work without compromising their quality of life in the workplace.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Yanli Zhang&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sowmiya Mathanagopalan&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/joonho-choi">Joon-Ho Choi&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required">Skills Required&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Matlab&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>