<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Spring 2021 | DataFirst</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/category/spring-2021/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/category/spring-2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Spring 2021</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Spring 2021</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/category/spring-2021/</link></image><item><title>Detecting Biases in College Football Recruiting (Spring - 2021) (Spring - 2021)</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/12/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>College football recruiting is big business. This project aims to build and analyze a comprehensive college football recruiting dataset, to help determine if there are biases in who and how college football coaches recruit players. This data set will combine college football recruiting data from the web with census and other socioeconomic data, to search for patterns in where and how college football coaches recruit players.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/manasi-godse">Manasi Godse&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jackie-fan">Jackie Fan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yash-gupta">Yash Gupta&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/rehan-ahmed">Rehan Ahmed&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jiahang-song">Jiahang Song&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/jeremy-abramson">Jeremy Abramson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>APIs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Databases&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web Scraping&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SQL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NoSQL&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Drought prediction in Southern California using deep learning</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Seasonal drought predictions are important for the management of water resources for agriculture, urban consumption… Seasonal forecasts have traditionally been done using a physics-based model. In this project, we will use a deep learning approach for drought forecasting in CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/shubhashree-dash">Shubhashree Dash&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/katie-chak">Katie Chak&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/deborah-khider">Deborah Khider&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PyTorch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deep Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Investigating disparities in the COVID-19 epidemic in Los Angeles County through fine-grained epidemic modeling (Spring - 2021)</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Fine-grained epidemiological modeling of the spread of COVID-19 can inform public health policy that accounts for disparities in the risk of exposure, infection, and death across different locations and different demographic groups. In Los Angeles County, disparities in COVID-19 infection rates by neighborhood have been tremendous. Throughout the current large outbreak wave, infection incidence rates in low-income, predominantly Hispanic neighborhoods of East LA have consistently been 10-15 times higher than in wealthier, predominantly white neighborhoods in West LA. Many well-informed hypotheses exist to explain the cause of these disparities in infection, including employment sectors that require leaving homes to work, household density, and behavioral differences across cultures and age groups. But for Los Angeles County, these hypotheses have not been evaluated quantitatively in the context of an epidemic modeling framework.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To explain the disproportionate impact of the virus on disadvantaged demographic groups in Los Angeles County, we are developing a networked multiple-population epidemic model to investigate how epidemic dynamics and infection outcomes differ across fine-grained neighborhoods. Specifically, we will extend an already-developed stochastic SEIR+ disease model that includes healthcare, death, and vaccination compartments into the networked multiple-population framework, which will model movements, contacts, and infection pathways within and between neighborhoods. A key feature of this modeling framework will be the use of dynamic mobility data, derived from US cell phone data, to inform changes in the daily movements of people within and between neighborhoods. This data will provide the basis of a weighted infection-transmissible contact network between neighborhoods. The SEIR disease model is run on top of this contact network, determining infection dynamics across the neighborhoods. The model will allow obtaining estimates of key epidemic quantities including transmission rates (and the time-varying reproductive number, R(t)) and infection fatality rates for each neighborhood, and identifying the neighborhoods driving epidemic spread (through contacts within and across neighborhoods). Furthermore, hierarchical modeling techniques will be used to obtain estimates of infection and fatality rates for substrata representing combinations of ethnicity/race, age, and sex within each neighborhood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CKIDS PROJECT TASKS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the overarching goal of this project is to develop a multiple-population epidemic model for Los Angeles County (LAC) across a network of connected neighborhoods, it is also necessary to maintain a single-population model for LAC as a whole that estimates the epidemic parameters for this larger spatial level. Such a single-population model has been maintained since May 2020 by the USC Biostatistics COVID modeling team. This model serves two important purposes. First, since May 2020 it has supported the LAC Department of Public Health, which has requested updates on key epidemic predictions on a weekly basis. Second; the parameters estimated from the single population model will serve as prior distributions in the Bayesian parameter estimation framework used in the networked-neighborhood model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first task for the CKIDS student will be to re-implement the parameter estimation framework for the existing LAC-level model, such that parameters are estimated each week and fixed for future estimates forward in time. This can be done either through modification to the existing code and parameter estimation framework, written in R and using Approximate Bayesian Computation (ABC), or through a full reimplementation of the modeling code. The second task will be to maintain the model estimation and website displaying updates through weekly updates using data that comes directly from the LAC Department of Public Health. A third possible task, depending on the interest of the CKIDS student, will be to apply the modeling to California data, and other counties in California (so far it has only been applied to LAC data).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/tao-huang">Tao Huang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jianing-juliachen">Jianing (Julia) Chen&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/abigail-horn">Abigail Horn&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Computational Simulation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Looking at White Hat (?) Hacker Social Networks on Github (Spring - 2021)</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/9/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Open-source intelligence (“OSINT”) is a rapidly growing area of cybersecurity. This project seeks to explore OSINT information available on GitHub. Specifically, we will build and analyze a dataset comprised of users on GitHub who show a specific interest in GitHub repos related to hacking artifacts. This dataset and social network analysis could help us determine what attributes lead to “black hat” — or malicious — cyber actors.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Project Achievement&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/dat-nguyen">Dat Nguyen&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/wenwen-zheng">Wenwen Zheng&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/nai-cihliou">Nai Cih Liou&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/xinran-liang">Xinran Liang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/jeremy-abramson">Jeremy Abramson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Databases&lt;/li>
&lt;li>APIs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GraphQL&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Machine Learning to Analyze Rock Microstructures (Spring - 2021)</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/11/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Students will analyze images from optical microscopes that reveal features of materials and microstructures using machine learning techniques. These images have been collected by geologists, who use them to study the rock samples that they collect in the field and determine their properties and origins. We have a baseline system already implemented, and the goal is to improve it with new machine learning techniques, guided by the insights of our collaborating geologists.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Data Science Teamwork&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/xiaoyu-wang">Xiaoyu Wang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/stephen-iota">Stephen Iota&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/bolong-pan">Bolong Pan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/junyi-liu">Junyi Liu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/ming-lyu">Ming Lyu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yolanda-gil">Yolanda Gil&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/wael-abdalmageed">Wael Abd-Almageed&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Computer Vision&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Mapping the Ethical Concerns Surrounding AI Research</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the recent enthusiasm about algorithmic fairness and responsible AI, many conferences are encouraging or requiring a broader impact section to assess societal harms and benefits of the AI research being presented. In this project, we will analyze the themes of these sections, with a particular focus on the ethical issues being addressed and acknowledged. We will develop tools and methods to evaluate the harms and benefits of the presented research. The goal is to see how is the community helping AI research to be less harmful but more beneficial for society. For more background on work in this area, please review this workshop.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Data Science Collaboration Practices&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/chaitali-joshi">Chaitali Joshi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/param-bole">Param Bole&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/muhammad-oneebulhaqkhan">Muhammad Oneeb Ul Haq Khan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/madeleine-thompson">Madeleine Thompson&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/aparna-nair">Aparna Nair&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/fred-morstatter">Fred Morstatter&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AI ethics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Mapping the Uncanny Valley (Spring - 2021)</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/10/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While many stories involve the friendly and familiar, scary stories across cultures, from Hamlet to Yotsuya Kaidan to Siren Head involve beings that are almost—but not quite—human. Can these stories give us insight into the “nearly-human” uncanny valley? Initial results from our group say yes! While some research has explored the uncanny valley for images, the research is limited and previously unexplored in text format. If we can extract human emotions surrounding text descriptions, we can exploit an enormous array of data. Our goal this semester is to analyze our objective definitions of “fear” or “creepiness” in a story and test how the similarity of words to “human” make them more or less creepy. Moreover, we will explore what features of objects make them more or less scary. These findings share a direct relationship to AI and robotics where our goal is always to improve pleasant interactions and affability in human-computer and human-robot interactions. The students will build on initial work to apply NLP methods to these texts and improve upon existing initial results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/saurabh-jain">Saurabh Jain&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/athashree-vartak">Athashree Vartak&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/olivia-fryt">Olivia Fryt&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yilin-qi">Yilin Qi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jiashu-xu">Jiashu Xu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/keith-burghardt">Keith Burghardt&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NLTK&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NLP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keras&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Microtelcos and the Digital Divide in CA (Spring - 2021)</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The COVID-19 pandemic has reinvigorated calls to close the digital divide in the US and elsewhere. Without adequate Internet access, households are at a disadvantage in education, jobs, health, and other key dimensions of wellbeing. While local broadband markets are increasingly concentrated, there is also increased interest in exploring the role those small local operators (“microtelcos”) can play in serving in low-income and rural communities. These microtelcos range from small wireless cooperatives to mom-and-pop private ISPs to municipal-backed operators. This project seeks to a) map and identify the characteristics of communities where microtelcos are present in CA, and b) to examine whether microtelcos presence affects broadband service quality and adoption by businesses and households in the community. The project will use broadband deployment data collected by the CPUC (California Public Utilities Commission) and socioeconomic data from the Census Bureau.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Data Science Poster Award&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/asjad-asifjah">Asjad Asif Jah&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jonathan-gonzalez">Jonathan Gonzalez&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/hernan-galperin">Hernan Galperin&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GIS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Econometrics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Object Detection and Classification for Street Cleanliness</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In collaboration with the Sanitation Department of LA, IMSC has been developing a framework to automatically detect the cleanliness of streets as well as any special objects in need of removal. The framework makes use of machine learning technology trained on images/videos collected by the city and/or taken by citizens. The images taken by mobile cameras (e.g., LA City’s garbage collection trucks and/or citizens’ smartphones using our own MediaQ App) are transferred to the MediaQ server, then these images can be automatically classified based on predefined cleanliness indexes and object types (such as bulky item, illegal dumping). In this project, we will focus on the detection and classification of homeless encampments in LA streets. Recorded images/videos with GPS location data will be processed and the classification results will be displayed on a map to understand the distribution of homeless people in LA, which is essential data to study the homeless issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/trisha-sinha">Trisha Sinha&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/harsh-jaykumarjalan">Harsh Jaykumar Jalan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/ashwin-sakhare">Ashwin Sakhare&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/divya-manjunath">Divya Manjunath&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/nai-cihliou">Nai Cih Liou&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/seon-kim">Seon Kim&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Visualization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Computer Vision&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Omics and Aging in Killfish</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/6/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Students will analyze aging in the African turquoise killifish, a species with the shortest lifespan of all vertebrates. By analyzing multi-omic data over the lifetime of many individuals, we can begin to understand the cellular changes that reflect aging.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/deven-panchac">Deven Panchac&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/michael-mathew">Michael Mathew&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/akansha-das">Akansha Das&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/suchetha-bhat">Suchetha Bhat&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/shruti-krishnakumar">Shruti Krishna Kumar&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/berenice-benayoun">Berenice Benayoun&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jose-luisambite">Jose Luis Ambite&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Studying the Effects of Genes and Environment in Aging</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/7/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Students will analyze genomic and environmental data collected through the lifetime of individuals to investigate which genes and external conditions could be associated with aging. The goal of the project will be to reproduce an existing published paper and improve on its results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Interdisciplinary Data Science Team&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/meera-patel">Meera Patel&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/boya-li">Boya Li&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/haoyang-chen">Haoyang Chen&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/qinming-zhang">Qinming Zhang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/ming-yan">Ming Yan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/t-emarpawong">T. Em Arpawong&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yolanda-gil">Yolanda Gil&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Turning Cyber Data into Language</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2021-spring/8/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cyber ontologies such as STIX and ATT&amp;amp;CK can represent complex relationships between cyber threat actors, attacks, and infrastructure. While such representations are easily processed by computers, cyber analysts often prefer dealing with written text. Natural language ontologies like FrameNet represent language in a structured manner as well, but frame specifications are often not specific enough for a given domain (like cybersecurity). In this project, students will learn about cybersecurity threat ontologies and build a GUI web app tool that annotates provided cyber threat documents. No previous knowledge of cybersecurity necessary!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/ruoyu-li">Ruoyu Li&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/carol-varkey">Carol Varkey&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/rengapriya-aravindan">Rengapriya Aravindan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/chuqi-liu">Chuqi Liu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/ziheng-gong">Ziheng Gong&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/jeremy-abramson">Jeremy Abramson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flask&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Streamlit&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>