<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Asumi Suguro | DataFirst</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/asumi-suguro/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/asumi-suguro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Asumi Suguro</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Asumi Suguro</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/asumi-suguro/</link></image><item><title>Worldwide Survey Estimates of Maternal Bereavement</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/201/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/201/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Infant and child mortality rates have been steadily declining worldwide over the last fifty years. Without reservation, these trends represent good news for children and for their parents, but the link between child mortality and parents’ experiences, however, remains loosely defined. Documenting global inequality in maternal bereavement offers a window into how health disparities directly affect the lives and well-being of mothers. In this project, we will offer the first, global analysis of the prevalence of bereaved mothers by leveraging data collected between 2010 and 2018 from 168 countries. I request student support to expand current survey coverage. Student(s) will work to identify and access public-use, nationally-representative reproductive history survey data for select European, Asian, and Latin American countries to supplement current data coverage, and to offer direct estimations to compare to indirectly derived ones based on current fertility and mortality levels. Students will work to adapt code used for other surveys to generate descriptive statistics of the prevalence of ever bereaved mothers in each country. Students will also work to improve and supplement the illustration of key study findings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Data Science Teamwork&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Aditi Singh&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Madeleine Thompson&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Malika Seth&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Asumi Suguro&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/emily-smithgreenaway">Emily Smith-Greenaway&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required">Skills Required&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Stata&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>