<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Events | DataFirst</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/event/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Events</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 17:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Events</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/event/</link></image><item><title>Information Session for DataFirst Fall 2023</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/event/kickoff/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/event/kickoff/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://calendar.google.com/calendar/event?action=TEMPLATE&amp;amp;tmeid=NGw5Y3JjM29rbWhnODJsZGNtZWJpYWhxbHEgMTQ3YTIwNWUzOTNlYzk4N2I4ZDQ4YmIzYjAzYjU5MGI0YTU4YmQ5Y2UyOTgzOWRmOWEyMWU1ODI5N2U1NWM0ZkBn&amp;amp;tmsrc=147a205e393ec987b8d48bb3b03b590b4a58bd9ce29839df9a21e58297e55c4f%40group.calendar.google.com">&lt;img border="0" src="https://www.google.com/calendar/images/ext/gc_button1_en.gif">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="are-you-not-sure-if-datafirst-is-for-you">Are you not sure if DataFirst is for you?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Come to our information session and hear from faculty mentors about projects that will be part of DataFirst this Fall semester. Then you can decide if you want to sign up to participate.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-datafirst">What is DataFirst?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We are excited to announce the 10th CKIDS DataFest event for Fall 2023. It will be such a special event that we are renaming it DataFirst.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This event is an opportunity for data science students to learn to work in teams with people who have different skills, to learn about different application domains, and to work on projects that can only be done with creative ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CKIDS DataFirst is a semester-long event where faculty offer students an opportunity to work on real-world data science projects. Several faculty advisors propose a project, each with some data and goals that should be feasible in a semester. DataFirst kicks off with 1-slide faculty pitches to an audience of potentially interested students. Students submit their preferred projects and are assigned to one of their choices. Each project is assigned 4-5 students that will work as a team through the semester. The faculty advisor commits to meet with the students once a week, and may make available some senior student or postdoc in their group who knows the data well. The students commit to spending 8-10 hours a week on the project. Students participate in a mid-semester presentation to report on their progress, and a final event where they report on results and we give a couple dozen awards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Fall we will be providing stronger mentoring and guidance to students along the semester. We will also be allocating space for students to work together and to attend tutorials/panels/QA sessions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some DataFirst projects continue for several semesters, and some have led to publications and even helped jumpstart long-lived projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every semester we have had 10-20 projects, so that is about 50-100 students participating. The students tend to be Viterbi masters students (some data science, some computer science and some from industrial systems engineering), but some are undergraduates and some students are in other schools as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Come to our information session and hear from faculty mentors about projects that will be part of DataFirst this Fall semester. Then you can decide if you want to sign up to participate.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>