<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Economics | DataFirst</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/category/economics/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/category/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Economics</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Economics</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/category/economics/</link></image><item><title>Microtelcos and the Digital Divide in CA</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-spring/311/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-spring/311/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The broadband access market is increasingly dominated by a few large ISPs. However, small and medium-size operators (“microtelcos”) are critical to connectivity in low-income and rural communities in CA, serving markets of little interest to large operators. The primary goal of this project is to combine broadband infrastructure deployment data from the CPUC (California Public Utilities Commission) and socioeconomic data from the Census Bureau to understand the characteristics of the communities served by microtelcos, and to analyze whether the presence of a microtelco operator contributes to higher levels of connectivity in the community. The main technical challenge is to combine spatial data found in CPUC files with census block level data provided by the Census Bureau. This is part of an ongoing research program called Connected Communities and Inclusive Growth (CCIG).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/hernan-galperin">Hernan Galperin&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required">Skills Required&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>GIS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stata&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Measuring Pollution Benefits from Congestion Pricing Initiatives</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2019-fall/419/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2019-fall/419/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Using real-time big data from Los Angeles freeways on traffic and Aclima data on pollution measurements, this project will estimate the links between speed and pollution. Estimating this relationship properly is crucial for knowing the benefits that congestion pricing may generate in terms of pollution reduction. Computer Science methods will be used to guide the choice of policy intervention and guide prediction.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/antonio-bento">Antonio Bento&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required">Skills Required&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>