<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fall 2020 | DataFirst</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/tag/fall-2020/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/tag/fall-2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Fall 2020</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Fall 2020</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/tag/fall-2020/</link></image><item><title>A framework for enabling software comparison and classification</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/206/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/206/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The number of scientific products, including scientific software, has been steadily growing in the last years. This growth makes it difficult for researchers to understand all the latest code and publications available. A great body of research has attempted at classifying similar papers and literature. However, there aren’t to date good approaches for finding similar or related code. In this project, the students will analyze different unsupervised methods to find scientific software similarities based on a) An automated analysis of their dependencies; b) By classifying the main functionality of software components.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yi-xie">Yi Xie&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/bin-zhang">Bin Zhang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/mohan-krishnathota">Mohan Krishna Thota&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/param-bole">Param Bole&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/daniel-garijo">Daniel Garijo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sklearn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Manipulation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Brain morphometry from contrast-enhanced T1-weighted brain MRIs</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/208/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/208/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cancer remains the second leading cause of death in the US. However, recent advancements have increased cancer survivorship, now numbering tens of millions. Given this, there is tremendous interest in studying cancer-related cognitive impairment (CRCI) and CRCI due to chemotherapy or “chemobrain”, can afflict up to 78% of survivors. The neural substrates of CRCI are unknown and understanding this may improve survivors’ quality of life. The CRCI neuroimaging literature is still in its infancy and these studies have used small sample sizes from traditional research-dedicated nCE scans. Because conducting well-powered neuroimaging studies is very expensive, adapting clinical CE T1w scans could prove useful for CRCI and many other diseases like dementia. The promary objective of this project is to develop a novel deep learning method to generate nCE images from acquired CE T1w scans to allow accurate brain morphometry and be a plentiful source of inexpensive neuroimaging data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/ming-lyu">Ming Lyu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/danielle-sim">Danielle Sim&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/devansh-shah">Devansh Shah&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/ting-funglam">Ting Fung Lam&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/neda-jahanshad">Neda Jahanshad&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/mark-shiroishi">Mark Shiroishi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/paul-thompson">Paul Thompson&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>AI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Familiarity with MRIs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Characterizing the counter-narratives of climate change (Fall - 2020)</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/216/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/216/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Top climate scientists post their findings and views regularly on social media. These very scientists are met with tweets from those with opposing views, often containing vitriolic and false information. It is important that we can identify and characterize these tweets to understand the counter-narratives of climate change. We will address topics including false information, bot campaigns, and harassment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Data Collection&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/abhilash-pandurangan">Abhilash Pandurangan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/aditya-jajodia">Aditya Jajodia&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/sushmitha-ravikumar">Sushmitha Ravikumar&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/vanshika-sridharan">Vanshika Sridharan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/fred-morstatter">Fred Morstatter&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/deborah-khider">Deborah Khider&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Classification&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Collection&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Detecting Biases in College Football Recruiting (Fall - 2020)</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/213/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/213/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>College football recruiting is big business. This project aims to determine if there are biases in who and how college football coaches recruit players. By creating a comprehensive data set of college recruits and integrating relevant data with current socioeconomic markers (i.e. census data) we hope to determine if there are patterns in who and where football coaches recruit their players, regardless of talent.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/saurabh-jain">Saurabh Jain&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jackie-fan">Jackie Fan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/akansha-das">Akansha Das&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/jeremy-abramson">Jeremy Abramson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Science&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Social Science&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mapmaking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Economics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Digital Democracy: Using Social Media to Improve Political Discourse</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/215/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/215/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Politicians in modern democracies across the world have eagerly adopted social media for engaging their constituents, entering into direct dialogs with citizens. From the perspective of political actors, there is a need to continuously gather, monitor, analyze, and visualize politically relevant information from online social media with the goal to improve communication with citizens and voters. The goal of this proposal is to create a tool that enhances interaction and dialogue between political actors and their followers. This will be achieved by creating compact and comprehensive summaries that aggregate and visualize common narratives, thus, reducing the cognitive load required to read all the messages and streamlining the dialogue experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/alex-spangher">Alex Spangher&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yash-shah">Yash Shah&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/swetha-thomas">Swetha Thomas&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/hongyu-li">Hongyu Li&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/raveena-kshatriya">Raveena Kshatriya&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/abhi-thadeshwar">Abhi Thadeshwar&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/andr%c3%a9s-abeliuk">Andrés Abeliuk&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>NLP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Programming&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Generation of a Sports-based Introductory Data Science Curriculum to Increase Participation of Underrepresented Groups in STEM</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/211/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/211/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the requirements for success in the workforce become increasingly technical, there is a commensurate need for curricula that can engage and capture the imagination of students, especially those from traditionally underrepresented groups in STEM. One way to reach these groups is via curricula that appeals to contexts in which they’re familiar and engaged, such as sports. To that end, this project will explore the development of a sports-based introductory data science curriculum with the goal of engaging students who might otherwise not be interested in pursuing data science as a career. Students will work on generation of illustrative code examples/problem sets in Python using sports examples.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/everest-law">Everest Law&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/zhongying-wang">Zhongying Wang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/sushmitha-ravikumar">Sushmitha Ravikumar&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/jeremy-abramson">Jeremy Abramson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pedagogy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Social Science&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Integration of Frame Semantics to Cyber Ontologies</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/207/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/207/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cyber ontologies such as STIX and ATT&amp;amp;CK can represent complex relationships between cyber threat actors, attacks and infrastructure. While such representations are conducive to interoperability between systems, they are often unwieldy for human cyber analysts to deal with directly. Conversely, Natural language generation (NLG) frameworks like FrameNet represent language in a structured manner, but frame specifications are often not specific enough for specialized domains (such as cyber security). Leveraging and combining the semantic structure of both forms can create a tool that can translate cyber threat data in standard interoperable formats (such as STIX) to human-readable reports, via existing NLG frameworks. Working on a project such as this provides an opportunity for significant impact, as the fusion of these two structures could greatly increase both the adoption and the utility of cyber threat ontologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/folk-narongrit">Folk Narongrit&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/carol-varkey">Carol Varkey&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/francis-sun">Francis Sun&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/jeremy-abramson">Jeremy Abramson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NLP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Science&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OSINT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cybersecurity&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Investigations of a Data Science Online Community</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/202/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/202/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Kaggle.com competition ecosystem is a rich and active community with a designed Progression System that uses performance medals to rank and differentiate users into tiers. However, winning performance medals in Kaggle is more complex than it appears. Users are bound by the available competitions, characteristics of the competition’s problem statement, the quality of their software submissions, and the quality of other competitors (including collaborators). With these factors, one user’s earned “Gold” medal from one competition may have required more effort and a higher quality solution than another user’s earned “Gold” medal in a different competition. This project has great potential to learn about open competitions in data science. Some example questions are: What features help predict whether a user will win a medal in a competition? How can users be clustered and differentiated from one another using their competition patterns and medal-winning solutions? How quickly (in days) will a user win their next competition medal? What is the probability that a user will assemble a team for a competition? What are features that predict high-performing teams? What features help generate teammate recommendations?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Interdisciplinary Data Science Team&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/sara-melotte">Sara Melotte&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/devendra-swami">Devendra Swami&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jacob-bickman">Jacob Bickman&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jae-youngkim">Jae Young Kim&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/kevin-tsang">Kevin Tsang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/marlon-twyman">Marlon Twyman&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Matlab&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Machine Learning to Analyze Rock Microstructures (Fall - 2020)</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/210/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/210/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Students will analyze images from optical microscopes that reveal features of materials and microstructures using machine learning techniques. These images have been collected by geologists, who use them to study the rock samples that they collect in the field and determine their properties and origins. We have a baseline system already implemented, and the goal is to improve it with new machine learning techniques, guided by the insights of our collaborating geologists.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Project Presentation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/abhivineet-veeraghanta">Abhivineet Veeraghanta&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/bolong-pan">Bolong Pan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/bryan-beh">Bryan Beh&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/hanzhi-zhang">Hanzhi Zhang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/feilong-wu">Feilong Wu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/yolanda-gil">Yolanda Gil&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Image Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Mapping the impacts of climate change across LA County</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/205/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/205/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We are increasingly hyper-aware of the effects of climate change. But we are not always aware of how hyper-local those effects can be. Across the 2,500 square miles of Los Angeles County, the impact of climate change is playing out in different ways. For example, some areas are experiencing more frequent spikes in extreme temperatures, while others are not. We propose a project that would fuse together several different datasets in order to map how temperature changes and other variables are hitting some corners of Los Angeles harder than others. Often, these areas are inhabited by people facing numerous other inequities, such as poor healthcare access. By examining several years’ worth of hourly average temperatures from thousands of spots across Los Angeles County, and combining that with other datasets, such as tree cover, cases of asthma, and so forth, it is possible to create an interactive map that illustrates where the impacts of climate change are most acute. This project would be published by Annenberg’s Crosstown publishing outlet and would be distributed widely. The project would have immediate practical applications and could inform policy decisions on issues such as where to place parks and green spaces.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Interdisciplinary Data Science Team&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/simon-khan">Simon Khan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/vinith-angadi">Vinith Angadi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yingxi-lin">Yingxi Lin&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/shalini-mustala">Shalini Mustala&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/gabriel-kahn">Gabriel Kahn&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>GIS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SQL&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Mapping the Uncanny Valley (Fall - 2020)</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/204/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/204/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While many stories involve the friendly and familiar, scary stories across cultures, from Hamlet to Yotsuya Kaidan to Siren Head involve beings that are almost—but not quite—human. Can these stories give us insight into the “nearly-human” uncanny valley? And are the most popular stories at the nadir of this valley? In this project we aim to explore the uncanny valley through analysis of several thousand stories posted on Reddit posted over a decade. These data contain stories that cross a range of topics, and include user comments and story scores. We will explore the prevalence of the monsters over time, and explore whether there is some optimal characteristics of these monsters that make them so scary. While some research has explored the uncanny valley for images, the research is limited and virtually unexplored in text format. The students will build on initial work by the advisor to apply NLP methods to these texts and improve upon existing initial results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Cyberphysical Data Science Team&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yuchen-zhang">Yuchen Zhang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/naicih-liou">Nai-Cih Liou&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/haripriya-dharmala">Haripriya Dharmala&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/sakshi-goel">Sakshi Goel&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/raveena-kshatriya">Raveena Kshatriya&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/keith-burghardt">Keith Burghardt&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NLTK&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NLP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keras&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gensim&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Social Graph Analysis and Attribution of Software Exploit Contributors Using GitHub</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/209/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/209/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Attribution of cyber threat actors is an increasingly important and difficult problem. One potential mitigation is the early detection of potential threat actors via analysis of open-source intelligence (OSINT). This project will analyze the social graph of users who contribute to, follow, star, and otherwise interact with proof-of-concept CVE implementations and other relevant potentially malicious (e.g. software vulnerability) repositories on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/atharva-rishi">Atharva Rishi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/erin-szeto">Erin Szeto&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jiaxin-liang">Jiaxin Liang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/kshitij-gupta">Kshitij Gupta&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/nghi-le">Nghi Le&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/erica-xia">Erica Xia&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/jeremy-abramson">Jeremy Abramson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Science&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cybersecurity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graph Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Team Dynamics in Online Multiplayer Games</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/217/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/217/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Competitive online multiplayer team games such as CounterStrike, PUBG, or League of Legends are extremely popular. Multiple teams of professional players compete in hundreds of tournaments yearly. Player transfer between teams is common. The goal of the project is to measure the effects of player transfers and to answer some of the questions such as: How does a new player affect the team’s performance?; How does the change of a team affect a player’s performance? The world of online games can be used as a fruitful area for tackling more fundamental questions on human society and collaboration dynamics in different settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/kevin-tsang">Kevin Tsang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/jiaqi-liu">Jiaqi Liu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/goran-muric">Goran Muric&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The aging individual brain</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/203/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/203/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Deep learning models are now able to predict how an individual’s face will age in a very realistic manner — ensuring key individual features, for example eye color, are maintained, while more age related features, such as the texture of skin, are altered to be representative of a desired age group. However, little work has been done to try and predict how an individual’s brain will age. Such models may be able to help predict early signatures of neurodegenerative disorders. The goal of this project will be to test several models to realistically predict how a given individual’s brain will look at any age in mid to late adulthood. Either or both deep learning based and image processing based methods would be encouraged. Students will work with a dataset of over 20,000 brain scans of individuals aged 45-80, approximately 1000 of whom have a scan again after two years. This is currently an active project in the lab and students will join researchers already working on this problem to further explore and improve methodology.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/aleck-cervantes">Aleck Cervantes&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/david-lin">David Lin&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/shunlin-lu">Shunlin Lu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/tianyu-zhu">Tianyu Zhu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yichao-zhu">Yichao Zhu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/neda-jahanshad">Neda Jahanshad&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deep Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Git&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Tracking health and nutrition signals from social media data</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/214/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/214/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This project will explore the ability to track real-life health and nutrition signals from social media data, focusing on data from Instagram and Foursquare. We will investigate the quality of Instagram posts as a source of data for measurements of dietary patterns and nutrition quality, focusing on spatial, textual, and (&lt;em>new in this semester&lt;/em>) image content of posts linked to food outlets in Los Angeles, as well as nutritional content analysis of menus available online. Multiple aims will be investigated in this project, including: scraping data from social media; NLP of tag, comments, and menu data; image analysis; predictive models and social network analysis; and more. Also new in this semester: “ground truth” data on dietary patterns of LA residents will be available, enabling validation of dietary measures and predictive models built from Instagram posts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project will build on the DataFest 2019 project, and will expand the scope to actually access up-to-date data from Instagram, in particular: data with images, the underlying social connections / social network, and of course more timely (which requires data scraping).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/abhilash-karpurapu">Abhilash Karpurapu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/erica-xia">Erica Xia&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/iris-liu">Iris Liu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/spoorti-nidagundi">Spoorti Nidagundi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/abigail-horn">Abigail Horn&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/andr%c3%a9s-abeliuk">Andrés Abeliuk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/kayla-delahaye">Kayla de la Haye&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yelena-mejova">Yelena Mejova&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NLP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistical Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Social Network Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sentiment Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Image Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>User-centered building design preference assessment to develop data-driven interactive architectural design guideline models</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/212/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/212/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In many architectural designing scenarios, architects and clients inevitably spend a lot of time determining design agreements due to a lack of understanding about the client’s design needs and preferences. An architectural design process could be significantly expedited and simplified if modeling software can accurately extract the user’s preferred design features and integrate them into the design process. In this project, we addressed the challenges of demonstrating a stochastic model with the consideration of the user’s physiological responses and subjective design perceptions by using data analytic methods. This technical principle exploited personal design preferences that would adopt them to the design process to effectively complete an architecture project.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/muhammad-oneebulhaqkhan">Muhammad Oneeb Ul Haq Khan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/adwaita-jadhav">Adwaita Jadhav&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/rosy-zhou">Rosy Zhou&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/yuka-kaku">Yuka Kaku&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/joonho-choi">Joon-Ho Choi&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sklearn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>WEKA&lt;/li>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Worldwide Survey Estimates of Maternal Bereavement</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/201/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2020-fall/201/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Infant and child mortality rates have been steadily declining worldwide over the last fifty years. Without reservation, these trends represent good news for children and for their parents, but the link between child mortality and parents’ experiences, however, remains loosely defined. Documenting global inequality in maternal bereavement offers a window into how health disparities directly affect the lives and well-being of mothers. In this project, we will offer the first, global analysis of the prevalence of bereaved mothers by leveraging data collected between 2010 and 2018 from 168 countries. I request student support to expand current survey coverage. Student(s) will work to identify and access public-use, nationally-representative reproductive history survey data for select European, Asian, and Latin American countries to supplement current data coverage, and to offer direct estimations to compare to indirectly derived ones based on current fertility and mortality levels. Students will work to adapt code used for other surveys to generate descriptive statistics of the prevalence of ever bereaved mothers in each country. Students will also work to improve and supplement the illustration of key study findings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Best Data Science Teamwork&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/aditi-singh">Aditi Singh&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/madeleine-thompson">Madeleine Thompson&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/malika-seth">Malika Seth&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../author/asumi-suguro">Asumi Suguro&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advisors">Advisors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../author/emily-smithgreenaway">Emily Smith-Greenaway&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-required-by-the-team">Skills Required by the team&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Stata&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>