<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lei Cao | DataFirst</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/lei-cao/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/lei-cao/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Lei Cao</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Lei Cao</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/author/lei-cao/</link></image><item><title>Determinants of spatial variations in broadband quality and prices</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2023-spring/1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2023-spring/1/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is anecdotal evidence that broadband service offers vary in quality and price along income and racial lines. This project seeks to validate these claims by collecting data about service speeds and prices for all known serviceable locations in Los Angeles County, and merging with sociodemographic variables from the Census Bureau and other sources. Other researchers have already developed prototype code for scraping data from ISP&amp;rsquo;s websites, but the study only covered a small percentage of addresses in LA County. The analysis will probe for evidence of a &amp;ldquo;poverty penalty&amp;rdquo; whereby residents of poorer areas in Los Angeles are offered higher cost/lower quality broadband services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Networked social influence in large-scale networks</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2023-spring/5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/projects/2023-spring/5/</guid><description>&lt;p>We recently published a novel algorithm for measuring influence among people. What&amp;rsquo;s different about it is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t rely on social media. It takes behavior data, such as might exist within a company&amp;rsquo;s databases, and is able to say &amp;ldquo;This person is causing this person to do X.&amp;rdquo; This technique is broad and powerful and has many social and business applications. We&amp;rsquo;re also fortunate to have a lot of data from corporations to explore, including over a 100m person dataset on charitable giving, several datasets of video game play, and one on commercial travel. What we need are smart students who can learn the algorithm and help us run it, answering questions of both scholarly and commercial interest. We need horsepower, and we&amp;rsquo;re happy to help train, advise and add students to the many publications we see coming out of this effort.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>